# **Daehwa Kim**

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, which defines as a computer become a part of the environment and human body to enable seamless interaction so that users even unaware of it. My prior research lies in (a) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device, and (b) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques	sensing and interaction techniques for a <b>mobile device</b>	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated <b>hand inputs</b>
for Fluid Interfaces	OddEyeCam (UIST'20)  OmniSense (Under Review CHl'21)  + Complement    + Complement    - Compl	<ul><li>MagTouch (CHI'20)</li><li>AtaTouch (Under Review CHI'21)</li></ul>

#### **EDUCATION**

## **KAIST**, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
  - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (To be)
  - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
  - · Focus: Sensing Techniques

## UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
  - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
  - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
  - · Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

## **Gyeongsan Science High School**, High school diploma

Mar 2013 – Feb 2015

- Early graduated with UNIST President's Award.
- Club Activity: Physics Research Team, English Journal Club

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **CONFERENCES**

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [2] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

## **SUBMITTED**

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR controller Using RF Return-Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper)
- [2] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with OmniDirectional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper)

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## HCI Lab, KAIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing
  - Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
  - Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
  - · Focus: PCB design

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

	<ul> <li>Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI</li> <li>Research Intern, IoT Research Division         <ul> <li>Project: Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice</li> <li>Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim</li> <li>Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing</li> </ul> </li> <li>iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST</li> <li>Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering</li> <li>Project: Finger Joystick Interaction</li> <li>Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko</li> <li>Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization</li> </ul>	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018 Feb 2017 – Nov 2017
AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS	<ul> <li>4th Prize, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award</li> <li>Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction".</li> <li>Awarded by NAVER CEO.</li> <li>Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.</li> <li>Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016</li> <li>Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to universit</li> </ul>	Dec 2017  Dec 2016
	<ul> <li>Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency.</li> <li>Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1.</li> <li>Academic Achievement Award, UNIST</li> <li>2017 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.05/4.3</li> <li>2017 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.98/4.3</li> <li>2016 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.90/4.3</li> <li>2016 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.06/4.3</li> <li>2015 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.00/4.3</li> <li>Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST</li> <li>Entered with top honors.</li> <li>Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester.</li> <li>Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST</li> <li>Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London</li> </ul>	Jan 2018 Jul 2017 Feb 2016 Aug 2016 Jul 2015 Mar 2015 – Feb 2019
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST Instructor, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT) ■ Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016	Sep 2018 – Dec 2018 Feb 2017 – Dec 2017 Jul 2016 – Sep 2016
CAMPUS ACTIVITIES	<ul> <li>D2 factory, NAVER</li> <li>Campus Partner</li> <li>Hosted the 1st Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE</li> <li>HEXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST</li> <li>A computer security &amp; development research group</li> <li>Vice-President</li> <li>Head of Android development team</li> <li>Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members</li> <li>UNIST Media Center, UNIST</li> <li>Video Editor</li> <li>Representative work</li> <li>My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone</li> <li>Web drama: The town where engineers live</li> </ul>	Feb 2016 – Feb 2017  Feb 2016 – Feb 2017  Feb 2017 – Dec 2017  Mar 2015 – Feb 2017
PERSONAL PROJECTS	Audio Hero  ■ Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model  ■ Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing  VRone  ■ 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone  ■ Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019 Sep 2018 – Dec 2018
	System Light 2.0 @ ETRI	Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

- Building IoT system for lights
- Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing

**VibCat** Oct 2017 – Dec 2017

- Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

# Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

- Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Poem a moment Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

- An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper
- Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)
- Skills: Android programming

## **TUIT Android Lecture**

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students
- Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

**Mr.Bill** Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

- Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way
- Available on Google Play store (download 500+)
- Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2020-11-07 for Acme Corporation]